## **Professional Summary**

Software Engineer with 6 months of corporate experience as an intern. Experienced in Front-End development in working with UI teams to make user friendly reusable components in ReactJS with HTML5, CSS3 and JavaScript. Hands on experience in Amazon Web Services (AWS) in building application utilizing AWS Lambda, S3, Route53, API Gateways, and Transcoding. Good understanding of Java technologies and object oriented programming concepts.

#### **Technical Skills**

Languages: Java, Python, C

Web Services: HTML5, CSS3, PHP, JavaScript ES6, Bootstrap 4, Rest API, NodeJS, JSON, ReactJS, Django, Angular 6

Databases: MySQL, DynamoDB, Firebase

Cloud Services: AWS Lambda, S3, Route53, API Gateways, Transcoding

Testing Tools: Selenium, Junit, Appium, Jest, Jasmine, Karma

### **Education**

#### San Jose State University, California

Jan 2015 - Dec 2018

Bachelors of Science in Computer Science

## **Professional Experience**

### Software Engineering Intern, Compunnel Software Group

Jan 2019 - Jul 2019

- Worked on the staffline pro portal in agile environment using AWS cloud services to bring clients and job seekers together for a seamless hiring.
- Involved in various phases of Software Development Life Cycle (SDLC) of the application like Requirement gathering, Design,
   Analysis and Code development.
- Developed a video upload functionality in AWS serverless framework and nodeJS and transcoded the video to make it viewable in web format
- Worked extensively with Angular CLI and implemented features like Components, pipes, directives and services to develop a single page application in the frontend.
- Active participant throughout from project inception to code development and elaborate testing of various modules.

## Maths Workshop Facilitator, San Jose State University

Sep 2017 - May 2018

Facilitated 50 workshops in a semester to assist students in calculus and discrete maths which helped improve students grades by
a letter grade and supported students by implementing an environment for independent learning and providing test taking
strategies.

## **Academic Projects**

#### Mobile Mart [React, JavaScript]

Feb 2019 - Mar. 2019

- Designed and developed an e commerce responsive web application for buying mobile devices.
- Built interactive, reusable UI components in React using ES6/JSX based on progressive web application designs.
- Integrated the PayPal Payment API with the application to help users in express checkout.

# **Backtrack Android Application [Java, XML]**

Oct. 2018 - Dec. 2018

- Designed and developed an android application to track live location of people added in your network.
- Designed the architecture of the application and data flow to and from firebase.
- Responsible for executing unit tests and end to end tests in appium framework.

# Stock Images Application [PHP, JavaScript, AWS]

Nov. 2018 - Dec. 2018

- Created a web based stock image platform for users to buy and sell images.
- Implemented the Amazon Rekognition API for image recognition that improved search accuracy by 70%.
- Set up a continuous integration pipeline to ensure automatic deployment to AWS.

## Bloggers Spot [Django, Python, JavaScript, CSS]

Aug. 2018 - Sept. 2018

- Built a responsive web application that allows users to create their blogs and share within new and existing groups.
- Designed and developed the user interfaces with jQuery and Bootstrap frameworks.
- Build the server side using Diango framework implementing Rest APIs and CRUD operations for groups and users.